Michael Surdo

Well-rounded, problem solver with 8 years in managerial roles previously in startup environments and fast-growing small businesses. Gained experience across a variety of fields including Warehouse Management, Shipping/Receiving and Inventory Distribution, backend systems.. Self-motivated and teamwork-oriented. Always striving for personal best and that of my team.

832 Dekalb Ave., Apt 2i Brooklyn, NY 11221 **516-780-1893** micperdo@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

Revel Transit Inc, Inventory Manager

Feb 2020 - May 2022

- Collaborated with operations team to scale the spare parts inventory for expanding fleet size
- Collaborated on migrating the system to new ERP platform.
- Utilized ERP for constructing transfer orders, purchase orders, inventory adjustments, stock counting
- Developed systems for parts picking, barcode system and SOPs for intake of overseas container shipments and forklift operation
- Managed the distribution of spare parts between multiple NY locations and to 4 satellite operations across the US
- Monthly warranty claims for spare parts with overseas manufacturer NIU technologies
- Collaborated with supply chain and data teams on order forecasting using on the ground experience and historical data gathering.
- Used operational experience to support ground ops during peak seasonal demand

Uncommon Goods, Operations Lead (Seasonal)

Oct 2019-Jan 2020

- Exported orders from Fulfillment Dashboard
- Prepared and collated work to be distributed to pickforce
- Gauging order volume and staffing to find equilibriums in workflow

Upper 90, Hicksville, New York— Warehouse Manager

Jan 2016 - 2019

- Manage inventory HUB that processes new stock and oversee the distribution of inventory across 4 retail locations.
- Maintain a warehouse with strong organization. Implemented a new layout that increased pulling efficiency and a grid system for outbound products.
- Coordinate the weekly distribution of product to stores via Upper 90 truck deliveries or with UPS Ground shipments.
- Base staff of 3-5 employees, delegating tasks in English and Spanish.
- Led a company wide change into a new inventorying process and gave on-site tutorials for store managers.

SKILLS

Netsuite
Excel (pivot tables, vlooks
e.g)
Slack
Google Drive Suite
Smartsheet
Lightspeed POS
Magento
Forklifting via pallet racks
Transit Van driving in NYC

EDUCATION

Hunter College Aug 2016-currently enrolled

Farmingdale State College Aug 2013-Sept 2015, Dean's List 4 semesters

Nassau Community College 2009-2011, Dean's List 4 semesters

LANGUAGES

Spanish (fluent)

Italian (conversational)

German (conversational)

English (fluent)

Python (intermediate)

Upper 90, Hicksville, New York—Web Fulfillment Manager

Sep 2014-2019

- Oversee the fulfillment of orders placed on u90soccer.com from the shipping HUB.
- Implemented quality control in the picking, packing and UPS shipment of orders.
- Prioritize timeliness and accuracy of shipments throughout high volume periods like Black Friday and major seasonal periods.
- Daily use of heat press machines to heat press customized apparel.
- Daily use of Adobe Illustrator and cutting machines for vinyl customization.

Upper 90, Hicksville, New York— Retail Manager

August 2013-Sep 2014

- Opened a new Upper 90 location, managing a staff of 5 employees with a co-manager.
- Daily customer interaction in sales and customer service with a focus on optimizing customer experience from start to finish.
- Worked opening and closing shifts, arming and disarming the alarm system and locking up shop.
- Safe-box deposits for daily cash sales and weekly bank deposits.
- Weekly sales reporting and summaries for ownership.